utterance_id,conversation_id,text,speaker_id,character_name,gender,movie_id,movie_name,release_year,rating,votes,genre,entities,sentiment
L865,L862,Thank God!  If I had to hear one more story about your coiffure...,u2,CAMERON,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('one', 'CARDINAL')]",0.5983
L860,L860,"Then Guillermo says, ""If you go any lighter, you're gonna look like an extra on 90210.""",u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Guillermo', 'PERSON'), ('90210', 'DATE')]",0.3612
L662,L662,Have fun tonight?,u2,CAMERON,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('tonight', 'TIME')]",0.5106
L576,L575,"Looks like things worked out tonight, huh?",u2,CAMERON,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('tonight', 'TIME')]",0.3612
L405,L404,"Lesbian?  No. I found a picture of Jared Leto in one of her drawers, so I'm pretty sure she's not harboring same-sex tendencies.",u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Lesbian', 'NORP'), ('Jared Leto', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')]",0.5916
L368,L367,"Eber's Deep Conditioner every two days. And I never, ever use a blowdryer without the diffuser attachment.",u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Eber', 'PERSON'), ('Deep Conditioner', 'PERSON'), ('every two days', 'DATE')]",-0.2235
L275,L271,Forget French.,u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('French', 'NORP')]",-0.2263
L202,L200,"The thing is, Cameron -- I'm at the mercy of a particularly hideous breed of loser.  My sister.  I can't date until she does.",u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Cameron', 'PERSON')]",-0.2263
L194,L194,Can we make this quick?  Roxanne Korrine and Andrew Barrett are having an incredibly horrendous public break- up on the quad.  Again.,u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Roxanne Korrine', 'PERSON'), ('Andrew Barrett', 'PERSON')]",-0.624
L600,L598,All I know is -- I'd give up my private line to go out with a guy like Joey.,u3,CHASTITY,?,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Joey', 'PERSON')]",0.3612
L595,L595,"He practically proposed when he found out we had the same dermatologist. I mean. Dr. Bonchowski is great an all, but he's not exactly relevant party conversation.",u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Bonchowski', 'PERSON')]",-0.0867
L593,L592,My agent says I've got a good shot at being the Prada guy next year.,u4,JOEY,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Prada', 'ORG'), ('next year', 'DATE')]",0.4404
L589,L589,"So yeah, I've got the Sears catalog thing going -- and the tube sock gig "" that's gonna be huge.  And then I'm up for an ad for Queen Harry next week.",u4,JOEY,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Sears', 'ORG'), ('Queen Harry', 'PERSON'), ('next week', 'DATE')]",0.5849
L982,L982,"You looked beautiful last night, you know.",u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('last night', 'TIME')]",0.5994
L913,L909,"Not all experiences are good, Bianca. You can't always trust the people you want to.",u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Bianca', 'ORG')]",0.1275
L898,L893,But you hate Joey,u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Joey', 'PERSON')]",-0.7227
L889,L889,"Listen, I know you hate having to sit home because I'm not Susie High School.",u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Susie High School', 'ORG')]",-0.5719
L533,L531,"Yeah, he's your freak friend Mandella's boyfriend.  I guess since I'm not allowed to go out, I should obsess over a dead guy, too.",u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Mandella', 'PERSON')]",-0.5859
L529,L529,Can't you forget for just one night that you're completely wretched?,u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('just one night', 'TIME')]",0.1695
L527,L525,"Bogey Lowenstein's party is normal, but you're too busy listening to Bitches Who Need Prozac to know that.",u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[(""Bogey Lowenstein's"", 'ORG'), ('Bitches Who Need Prozac', 'PERSON')]",-0.6705
L443,L441,"Oh, I thought you might have a date  I don't know why I'm bothering to ask, but are you going to Bogey Lowenstein's party Saturday night?",u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[(""Bogey Lowenstein's"", 'ORG'), ('Saturday night', 'TIME')]",0.4118
L442,L441,It means that Gigglepuss is playing at Club Skunk and we're going.,u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Gigglepuss', 'PERSON'), ('Club Skunk', 'ORG')]",0.2023
L881,L878,"It's that hot rod Joey, right? That ' s who you want me to bend my rules for?",u11,WALTER,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Joey', 'PERSON')]",0.168
L878,L878,"Daddy, I want to discuss the prom with you. It's tomorrow night --",u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('tomorrow', 'DATE'), ('night', 'TIME')]",0.0772
L521,L517,"It's just a party. Daddy, but I knew you'd forbid me to go since ""Gloria Steinem"" over there isn't going --",u0,BIANCA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Gloria Steinem', 'PERSON')]",-0.2732
L459,L458,Didn't have you pegged for a Gigglepuss fan.  Aren't they a little too pre-teen belly-button ring for you?,u1,BRUCE,?,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Gigglepuss', 'PERSON')]",0.3182
L458,L458,"Always a pleasure, Brucie.",u9,PATRICK,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Brucie', 'PERSON')]",0.5719
L419,L416,Dead at forty-one.,u7,MICHAEL,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('forty-one', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.6486
L388,L388,This is it.  A golden opportunity. Patrick can ask Katarina to the party.,u2,CAMERON,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Patrick', 'PERSON'), ('Katarina', 'PERSON')]",0.6705
L245,L244,"Like we had a choice?  Besides -- when you let the enemy think he's orchestrating the battle, you're in a position of power. We let him pretend he's calling the shots, and while he's busy setting up the plan, you have time to woo Bianca.",u7,MICHAEL,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Bianca', 'ORG')]",-0.2263
L218,L215,They always let felons sit in on Honors Biology?,u2,CAMERON,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Honors Biology', 'ORG')]",0.5106
L217,L215,No kidding.  He's a criminal.  I heard he lit a state trooper on fire.  He just got out of Alcatraz...,u7,MICHAEL,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Alcatraz', 'GPE')]",-0.765
L210,L210,"I teach her French, get to know her, dazzle her with charm and she falls in love with me.",u2,CAMERON,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('French', 'NORP')]",0.7845
L144,L143,Sure do ... my Mom's from Canada,u2,CAMERON,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Canada', 'GPE')]",0.3182
L142,L139,"Joey Dorsey?  Perma-shit-grin.  I wish I could say he's a moron, but he's number twelve in the class.  And a model.  Mostly regional stuff, but he's rumored to have a big tube sock ad coming out.",u7,MICHAEL,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Joey Dorsey', 'PERSON'), ('Perma', 'LOC'), ('twelve', 'CARDINAL')]",0.0516
L78,L77,"Yeah, but these guys have never seen a horse.  They just jack off to Clint Eastwood.",u7,MICHAEL,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('jack', 'PERSON'), ('Clint Eastwood', 'ORG')]",0.1531
L74,L66,Couple thousand. Most of them evil,u7,MICHAEL,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Couple thousand', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.6872
L740,L740,She hates you with the fire of a thousand suns .  That's a direct quote,u2,CAMERON,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('thousand', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.6486
L623,L623,Cameron -- do you like the girl?,u9,PATRICK,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Cameron', 'PERSON')]",0.3612
L430,L430,Gigglepuss is playing there tomorrow night.,u2,CAMERON,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('tomorrow night', 'TIME')]",0.2023
L426,L426,"Okay -- Likes:  Thai food, feminist prose, and ""angry, stinky girl music of the indie-rock persuasion"".",u2,CAMERON,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Thai', 'NORP')]",0.296
L412,L411,I've retrieved certain pieces of information on Miss Katarina Stratford I think you'll find helpful.,u2,CAMERON,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Katarina Stratford', 'PERSON')]",0.5106
L149,L148,"Yeah, and I noticed the only part of you featured in your big Kmart spread was your elbow.  Tough break.",u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Kmart', 'ORG')]",0.1779
L748,L747,Enough with the Barbie n' Ken shit. I know.,u4,JOEY,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Barbie', 'PERSON'), ('Ken', 'PERSON')]",-0.5574
L299,L298,"Fine, thirty.",u4,JOEY,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('thirty', 'DATE')]",0.2023
L298,L298,I can't take a girl like that out on twenty bucks.,u9,PATRICK,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('twenty bucks', 'MONEY')]",-0.2755
L294,L294,"You got it, Verona.  I pick up the tab, you do the honors.",u4,JOEY,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Verona', 'PERSON')]",0.5106
L289,L287,"Sure, Sparky.  I'll get right on it.",u9,PATRICK,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Sparky', 'PERSON')]",0.3182
L287,L287,"Two legs, nice rack...",u9,PATRICK,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Two', 'CARDINAL')]",0.4215
L752,L750,"Listen to you!  You sound like Betty, all pissed off because Archie is taking Veronica.",u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Betty', 'ORG'), ('Archie', 'PRODUCT'), ('Veronica', 'PRODUCT')]",-0.4574
L719,L716,I did Bianca a favor and it backfired.,u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Bianca', 'ORG')]",0.4019
L254,L252,"If I was Bianca, it would be, ""Any school you want, precious.  Don't forget your tiara.""",u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Bianca', 'ORG')]",0.6874
L247,L247,"So he has this huge raging fit about Sarah Lawrence and insists that I go to his male-dominated, puking frat boy, number one golf team school. I have no say at all.",u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Sarah Lawrence', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.4543
L152,L151,You could always go with me.  I'm sure William has some friends.,u6,MANDELLA,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('William', 'PERSON')]",0.6597
L133,L133,"I realize that the men of this fine institution are severely lacking, but killing yourself so you can be with William Shakespeare is beyond the scope of normal teenage obsessions.  You're venturing far past daytime talk show fodder and entering the world of those who need very expensive therapy.",u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('William Shakespeare', 'PERSON')]",-0.8735
L129,L129,"Mandella, eat.  Starving yourself is a very slow way to die.",u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Mandella', 'NORP')]",-0.7717
L974,L973,You were paid to take me out!  By -- the one person I truly hate.  I knew it was a set-up!,u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('one', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.3365
L959,L957,"That's where I was last year.  She'd never lived alone -- my grandfather died -- I stayed with her.  I wasn't in jail, I don't know Marilyn Manson, and I've never slept with a Spice Girl.  I spent a year sitting next to my grandma on the couch watching Wheel of Fortune.  End of story.",u9,PATRICK,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('last year', 'DATE'), ('Marilyn Manson', 'PERSON'), ('Spice Girl', 'PERSON'), ('a year', 'DATE'), ('Wheel of Fortune', 'ORG')]",-0.4329
L764,L764,"Excuse me, have you seen The Feminine Mystique?  I lost my copy.",u9,PATRICK,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('The Feminine Mystique', 'FAC')]",-0.25
L481,L481,"You know, these guys are no Bikini Kill or The Raincoats, but they're right up there.",u9,PATRICK,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Raincoats', 'PERSON')]",-0.5346
L312,L311,"Like where?  The 7-Eleven on Burnside? Do you even know my name, screwboy?",u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('7-Eleven', 'EVENT')]",0.466
L998,L998,"You know, fathers don't like to admit that their daughters are capable of running their own lives.  It means we've become spectators.  Bianca still lets me play a few innings.  You've had me on the bleachers for years.  When you go to Sarah Lawrence, I won't even be able to watch the game.",u11,WALTER,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Bianca', 'ORG'), ('years', 'DATE'), ('Sarah Lawrence', 'PERSON')]",0.3178
L994,L989,The part where Bianca beat the hell out of some guy.,u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Bianca', 'ORG')]",-0.6808
L347,L338,I want to go to an East Coast school! I want you to trust me to make my own choices.  I want --,u5,KAT,f,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('East Coast', 'LOC')]",0.6696
L346,L338,You're eighteen.  You don't know what you want.  You won't know until you're forty-five and you don't have it.,u11,WALTER,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('eighteen', 'DATE'), ('forty-five', 'CARDINAL')]",0.0772
L340,L338,Is this about Sarah Lawrence? You punishing me?,u11,WALTER,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Sarah Lawrence', 'PERSON')]",-0.6072
L105,L103,"Well, yes, compared to your other choices of expression this year, today's events are quite mild.  By the way, Bobby Rictor's gonad retrieval operation went quite well, in case you're interested.",u8,MISS PERKY,?,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('this year', 'DATE'), ('today', 'DATE'), (""Bobby Rictor's"", 'PERSON')]",0.8357
L103,L103,"Katarina Stratford.  My, my.  You've been terrorizing Ms. Blaise again.",u8,MISS PERKY,?,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Katarina Stratford', 'PERSON'), ('Blaise', 'PERSON')]",-0.6124
L383,L383,You two are gonna help me tame the wild beast?,u9,PATRICK,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('two', 'CARDINAL')]",0.4019
L378,L378,I think I speak correctly when I say that Cameron's love is pure.  Purer than say -- Joey Dorsey's.,u7,MICHAEL,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Cameron', 'ORG'), (""Joey Dorsey's"", 'PERSON')]",0.6369
L377,L375,What is it with this chick?  She have three tits?,u9,PATRICK,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('three', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.3094
L257,L257,"I don't understand, Patrick.  You haven't done anything asinine this week. Are you not feeling well?",u8,MISS PERKY,?,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Patrick', 'PERSON'), ('this week', 'DATE')]",-0.2924
L917,L917,"What do you wanna watch?  We've got crap, crap, crap or crap",u11,WALTER,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('wanna', 'PERSON')]",-0.8555
L887,L886,Kissing?  Is that what you think happens?  Kissing isn't what keeps me up to my elbows in placenta all day.,u11,WALTER,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('Kissing', 'PERSON'), ('all day', 'DATE')]",0.8299
L876,L876,Would you rather be ravished by a pirate or a British rear admiral?,u10,SHARON,?,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('British', 'NORP')]",0.3182
L162,L161,Make anyone cry today?,u11,WALTER,m,m0,10 things i hate about you,1999,6.9,62847,"[, ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', r, o, m, a, n, c, e, ', ]","[('today', 'DATE')]",-0.4767
L2172,L2170,You'll be drinking your own piss... For the glory of Spain... and Admiral Colon...!  Bastard!,u12,ALONSO,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Spain', 'GPE'), ('Bastard', 'ORG')]",0.4374
L2170,L2170,I never seen heat like this!  Not even in Las Minas!,u12,ALONSO,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Las Minas', 'FAC')]",-0.4007
L2019,L2019,"If God intended our proximity to Asia, do you believe he would have waited for you to show it to the world?",u13,AROJAZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Asia', 'LOC')]",0.2732
L2016,L2014,"No.  The Portuguese have already discovered black-skinned people.  I, too, will find other populations -- and bring them to the word of God.",u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Portuguese', 'NORP')]",-0.0258
L2014,L2014,"Trade, Your Excellency.  According to Marco Polo, the Kingdom of China is one of the richest of the world. Even the meanest buildings are roofed with gold.",u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Marco Polo', 'PERSON'), ('the Kingdom of China', 'GPE')]",0.7845
L2005,L2005,"Senor Colon, an experienced captain such as yourself will understand our concern with the crew.  I am not willing to have on my conscience the loss of men who would have relied upon our judgment.",u13,AROJAZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Senor Colon', 'PERSON')]",-0.3182
L1993,L1989,"Then you cannot ignore that according to their calculations, the circumference of the Earth is approximately...  22,000 leagues or more.  Which makes the ocean... uncrossable.",u13,AROJAZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Earth', 'LOC'), ('22,000', 'CARDINAL')]",0.2755
L1991,L1989,"Unfortunately, Don Colon, that is precisely where our opinions differ...  Are you familiar with the work of Aristotle?  Erathostene?  Ptolemeus?",u13,AROJAZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Don Colon', 'PERSON'), ('Aristotle', 'PERSON'), ('Erathostene', 'PERSON'), ('Ptolemeus', 'PERSON')]",-0.4479
L1990,L1989,"Yes, your Eminence.  The voyage should not take more than six or seven weeks.",u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('more than six or seven weeks', 'DATE')]",0.4019
L2274,L2274,"It won't be easy to get rid of your prophet now, Don Sanchez.",u13,AROJAZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Don Sanchez', 'PERSON')]",-0.3412
L2031,L2030,"Indeed.  The world is full of mercenaries -- and states often make use of them, when it benefits them.  My only concern is the welfare and prosperity of Spain.",u24,SANCHEZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Spain', 'GPE')]",0.3818
L2030,L2030,He is a mercenary!  Did he not already try to convince the King of Portugal of his absurd notions?,u13,AROJAZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('the King of Portugal', 'WORK_OF_ART')]",0.3164
L2029,L2027,Naturally.  But I would really deplore the loss of such a potential opportunity for Spain for a... dispute over a point of geography.,u24,SANCHEZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Spain', 'GPE')]",-0.4932
L2027,L2027,"The State has some reason to be interested in this man's proposition, Your Eminence...",u24,SANCHEZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('State', 'ORG')]",0.4019
L2318,L2318,"Beatrix, I want to ask you something.",u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Beatrix', 'GPE')]",0.0772
L2430,L2429,I am not a seaman.  But I heard it is no more than a week at sea.  I hope you are not too disappointed.,u15,BOBADILLA,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('no more than a week', 'DATE')]",0.6576
L2291,L2290,"Forgive me, Don Bobadilla -- those positions have already been taken.",u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Don Bobadilla', 'PERSON')]",0.2732
L2484,L2484,"How are you feeling, Fernando?",u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Fernando', 'PERSON')]",0.128
L2130,L2130,Do you swear on all the Holy Saints in heaven?,u17,FERNANDO,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('the Holy Saints', 'ORG')]",0.4767
L2129,L2127,You promise?  Do you swear on St. Christopher...?,u17,FERNANDO,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('St. Christopher', 'GPE')]",0.3527
L2296,L2295,"Don Bobadilla is already a judge, my Dear Don Cristobal.",u24,SANCHEZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Don Bobadilla', 'PERSON'), ('Dear Don Cristobal', 'WORK_OF_ART')]",0.3818
L2282,L2281,"Forgive me, Don Colon.  But what about gold?",u24,SANCHEZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Don Colon', 'PERSON')]",0.1406
L2106,L2106,"I remind you, Senor Colon, that you are in no position to bargain with me.",u24,SANCHEZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Senor Colon', 'PERSON')]",-0.1027
L2038,L2037,Wait!  I've waited seven years already!  How much longer do you want me to wait?,u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('seven years', 'DATE')]",0.2225
L1963,L1963,"Two minutes... and already you're a dead man.  Don't let passion overwhelm you, Colon.",u19,MARCHENA,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Two minutes', 'TIME')]",-0.7401
L1958,L1957,Ignorance!  I believe the Indies are no more than 750 leagues west of the Canary Islands.,u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Indies', 'ORG'), ('750', 'CARDINAL'), ('the Canary Islands', 'LOC')]",-0.6114
L1957,L1957,How can you be so certain?  The Ocean is said to be infinite.,u19,MARCHENA,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Ocean', 'ORG')]",0.4101
L1952,L1951,To open a new route to Asia.  At the moment there are only two ways of reaching it...,u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Asia', 'LOC'), ('only two', 'CARDINAL')]",0.2023
L1951,L1951,Why do you wish to sail west?,u19,MARCHENA,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('sail west', 'GPE')]",0.4019
L1942,L1942,"Diego is a bright boy -- a pleasure to teach -- but so serious... Brothers should be raised together, Colon.  Even brothers from different mothers...",u19,MARCHENA,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Diego', 'ORG'), ('Colon', 'PERSON')]",0.5106
L2458,L2456,"There is one thing I'd like to understand... Why do you want to go back, after all this?",u18,ISABEL,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('one', 'CARDINAL')]",0.4215
L2072,L2071,No more than the woman who said she would take Granada from the Moors.,u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Granada', 'GPE'), ('Moors', 'PRODUCT')]",-0.296
L2071,L2071,"I should not even be listening to you, since my council said no.  But Santangel tells me you are a man of honor and sincerity... And Sanchez, that you are not a fool.",u18,ISABEL,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Santangel', 'PERSON'), ('Sanchez', 'GPE')]",0.7788
L2388,L2386,"You'll be held in detention, deprived of your privileges and possessions.  Until you are returned to Spain where you will be judged. Have you anything to say?",u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Spain', 'GPE')]",-0.4588
L2386,L2386,"In one act of brutality, you have created chaos.  Tribes who were fighting each other are now joining forces against us!  All that because of your criminal savagery!",u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('Tribes', 'PERSON')]",-0.9492
L2333,L2331,"We came here to stay!  To build! Not to start a crusade.  In this forest, there is enough danger to sweep us away in days!  So we will be brave and swallow our grief.  And in the name of those who died, we will accomplish what we came for.",u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('days', 'DATE')]",-0.7074
L2331,L2331,You want a war?  Fine.  We are a thousand.  They outnumber us by ten! Who will you kill?  Which tribe?,u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('ten', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.8531
L2278,L2277,"The Indians have no such word, Don Moxica.",u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Indians', 'NORP'), ('Don Moxica', 'PERSON')]",-0.296
L2277,L2277,And you say this is an Indian vice? By God!  I don't see any kind of pleasure that would make this a sin.,u21,MOXICA,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Indian', 'NORP')]",0.1403
L2159,L2157,"Well, I surely know what a quadrant is!  But I've never seen it used at night before.",u20,MENDEZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('night', 'TIME')]",0.4199
L2197,L2196,"Six days ago, yes.",u16,COLUMBUS,m,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Six days ago', 'DATE')]",0.4019
L2196,L2196,You lied!  You cheated!  We're way past 750 leagues!,u22,PINZON,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('750', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.7767
L2415,L2414,"Is this true, Brother Buyl?",u18,ISABEL,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Buyl', 'PERSON')]",0.4215
L2414,L2414,... But there is worse.  He ordered the execution of five members of the nobility...,u24,SANCHEZ,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('five', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.631
L2112,L2112,"You were right, Don Sanchez... His demands could never be granted.",u18,ISABEL,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Don Sanchez', 'PERSON')]",-0.1877
L1930,L1930,"Is that the man I knew, Treasurer Sanchez?",u18,ISABEL,?,m1,1492: conquest of paradise,1992,6.2,10421,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', b, i, o, g, r, a, p, h, y, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', h, i, s, t, o, r, y, ', ]","[('Treasurer Sanchez', 'PERSON')]",0.128
L3489,L3482,"Yeah, he hated me from day when I was born.  Put it out.  Can you put the cigarette out?",u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('from day', 'DATE')]",-0.4588
L3478,L3464,"This is not about money, Emil.  I need your trust in me.",u26,CUTLER,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Emil', 'ORG')]",0.5106
L3477,L3464,Thirty-percent.  No more.  Or I call another lawyer.  This is the biggest case of your life.  Don't try to negotiate.  Thirty percent.  Say yes or no.,u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Thirty-percent', 'PERCENT'), ('Thirty percent', 'PERCENT')]",-0.1779
L3474,L3464,I would say...half.  Half is fair.,u26,CUTLER,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('half', 'CARDINAL')]",0.3182
L3469,L3464,"No, he is here.  Shit...",u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Shit', 'ORG')]",-0.296
L3468,L3464,Disappeared.  They're looking everywhere.  Maybe he went back to Czechoslovakia.,u26,CUTLER,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Czechoslovakia', 'GPE')]",-0.2263
L3459,L3459,"I brought you some letters.  It's really fan mail.  Women mostly.  One wants to buy you clothes, another sent a check. Another wants a check.",u26,CUTLER,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('One', 'CARDINAL')]",0.3804
L3383,L3383,Oh no!  No!  Shit!,u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Shit', 'ORG')]",-0.8349
L3309,L3309,A good Immigration lawyer could stall the process.  Eddie recommended one.,u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Eddie', 'PERSON'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')]",0.4404
L3306,L3305,Ludwig?  He's gay - are you jealous?,u27,DAPHNE,f,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Ludwig', 'ORG')]",-0.5204
L3167,L3167,"I came here.  I had no money.  I knew no one.  I couldn't get a job because you have to have a green card to get work. They approached me - I could've made a lot of money.  I considered it, but... it's not who I am.  They pay me below the table at Ludwig's.",u27,DAPHNE,f,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Ludwig', 'ORG')]",-0.5859
L3059,L3059,...my little sister and I shared a flat - I came home one night and a man was raping her.  His gun was on the chair... He came at me and I shot him.,u27,DAPHNE,f,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('one night', 'TIME')]",-0.7239
L3063,L3062,"I'm from a small town in Slovakia.  Like the South here.  The Police is right, a civilian is wrong.  So I fled.",u27,DAPHNE,f,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Slovakia', 'GPE'), ('South', 'LOC')]",-0.1531
L3047,L3045,"Tamina was a friend of mine.  My shower was broken, she let me use theirs.",u27,DAPHNE,f,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Tamina', 'ORG')]",0.0258
L3210,L3208,"Well, I'm the Deputy Chief Fire Marshall and every now and then I'd like to be included in decisions.",u28,DUFFY,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Fire Marshall', 'PERSON')]",0.296
L3504,L3498,"How are you going to fight this?  Maybe if Oleg hadn't gotten away and you'd been on the front page, as a hero, this thing would be easier to fight.  You'd have the good to weight against the bad! It's unfortunate that I have to make decisions based upon your press coverage but there's nothing I can do!  Gimme your shield.",u28,DUFFY,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Oleg', 'PERSON')]",-0.3147
L3198,L3198,Ladder 20 was on the Rock for training. We stopped there... so she could get cleaned up.,u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Ladder 20', 'PERSON')]",-0.2263
L3291,L3289,Alright.  Swing by her apartment.  Let her pick up her clothes and take her straight to Hoover Street.  You got that?,u28,DUFFY,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Hoover Street', 'FAC')]",0.4404
L2805,L2801,"You do that, wiseguy.  Now let's solve this thing before Eddie Flemming does.",u28,DUFFY,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Eddie Flemming', 'ORG')]",0.2023
L3028,L3027,"I know.  Relax.  Take it easy.  Don't worry, we'll get those fuckers.",u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Relax', 'GPE')]",0.5116
L3027,L3027,He got my gun!  Motherfucker was filming the whole time!,u36,LEON,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Motherfucker', 'ORG')]",-0.8217
L2603,L2602,What's the kid gonna say - sorry? Meanwhile I'm not here anymore. Like last week - we were at the morgue and this guy was all chopped up - spleen here - liver there - his heart in a pan. Six hours ago this guy was walkin' his dog or buyin' a quart of milk.  Who knows?  But some kid's robbed him for $3 or some shit and shot him and now you can't tell if he's a piece of beef or a human being and I'm thinkin' that's me. Sooner or later.  That's me.,u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('last week', 'DATE'), ('Six hours ago', 'TIME'), ('3', 'MONEY'), ('Sooner', 'PERSON')]",-0.7885
L2988,L2986,"Tall, short-haired, scary eyes.  Second guy with him was...shorter, with a wrestler's build.  And he wouldn't turn his videocamera off me.",u44,ROSE,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Second', 'ORDINAL')]",-0.4939
L2975,L2975,"Yeah.  He wanted a girl from Czechoslovakia, but I sent him Honey 'cause once they get there, you know, it doesn't really matter - Honey was killed...?  Poor girl...",u44,ROSE,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Czechoslovakia', 'GPE'), ('Honey', 'ORG')]",-0.6106
L2973,L2971,Oh my G-d.  Honey!  Honey's dead?,u44,ROSE,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Honey', 'ORG'), ('Honey', 'ORG')]",-0.68
L2972,L2971,"We don't have her I.D. yet, but one of your girls was killed last night at the King Edward Hotel.",u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('one', 'CARDINAL'), ('last night', 'TIME'), ('the King Edward Hotel', 'FAC')]",-0.8047
L2967,L2964,"Homicide, Miss Hearn.  It's Detective Eddie Flemming.  Open up.",u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Miss Hearn', 'PERSON')]",-0.1531
L3053,L3052,She just saw two of her friends killed! They probably threatened her.,u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('two', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.69
L2999,L2993,"Then I guess we're doin' this the right way, aren't we?  If we pull up to a burning building I'll gladly let you go first.",u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('first', 'ORDINAL')]",0.34
L2997,L2993,"Hey!  I always wanted to be a cop when I was a kid.  I dreamed of running up to a door, kicking it in, pulling my gun and yelling 'Freeze!' at the bad guy! What'd you dream about?",u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Freeze', 'PERSON')]",-0.6981
L2995,L2993,"So am I.  Alright, I'll go inside and you cover the back.",u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('I.  ', 'PERSON')]",0.3102
L2992,L2991,I'm on my way with Eddie.  Ludwig's. 63rd and Madison.  The suspects might be there already.,u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Eddie', 'ORG'), ('Ludwig', 'ORG'), ('Madison', 'PERSON')]",-0.34
L2903,L2899,My parents are from Poland.  I can help with the Eastern European angle.,u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Poland', 'GPE'), ('Eastern European', 'NORP')]",0.4019
L2897,L2895,Or Czechoslovakia.  The Slavs have been fighting the Germans and the Russians for a thousand years.  These are very intense people and they take things personally.,u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Czechoslovakia', 'GPE'), ('Slavs', 'PERSON'), ('Germans', 'NORP'), ('Russians', 'NORP'), ('a thousand years', 'DATE')]",-0.228
L2896,L2895,Eastern Europe.  Like what?  Romania? Hungary?,u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Eastern Europe', 'LOC'), ('Romania', 'GPE'), ('Hungary', 'GPE')]",0.466
L2895,L2895,"Maybe it's a ritual thing or someone trying to send a message.  Burial rites are taken very seriously in Eastern Europe.  It could be to humiliate them. Just burning them up, no proper funeral, it's like condemning them to hell.",u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Burial', 'LOC'), ('Eastern Europe', 'LOC')]",-0.9061
L2887,L2887,The Super said he'd seen her before but she didn't live here.,u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Super', 'ORG')]",0.3506
L2880,L2875,"Nah, why should you?",u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Nah', 'PERSON')]",-0.1027
L2877,L2875,"Nah, I musta missed it.",u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Nah', 'PERSON')]",-0.3818
L2731,L2730,"No, we don't mind.  You mind Leon?",u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Leon', 'PERSON')]",-0.296
L3249,L3248,"Smarter than Americans.  You're fed cry baby talk shows all day long.  Not only will Americans believe me, they'll cry for me.  So...Detective Eddie Flemming, would you like to say goodbye to your Nicolette? Maybe you can propose to her now?",u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Americans', 'NORP'), ('fed', 'ORG'), ('all day', 'DATE'), ('Americans', 'NORP'), ('Nicolette', 'PERSON')]",-0.264
L3148,L3148,"Okay, til tonight.",u41,NICOLETTE,f,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('tonight', 'TIME')]",0.2263
L3135,L3135,"Oh my G-d, they want me to anchor.  They want me to anchor tonight!",u41,NICOLETTE,f,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('tonight', 'TIME')]",0.2244
L3130,L3126,Okay.  Okay.  Hold that thought just for a second.  They only call me when it's an emergency.  Just hold that thought.  Can you call back?,u41,NICOLETTE,f,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('second', 'ORDINAL')]",0.0516
L3109,L3103,"Alright, alright, Eddie.  Don't patronize me.",u41,NICOLETTE,f,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Eddie', 'PERSON')]",0.4588
L3036,L3031,"Um...now is not a good time, okay. Detective Jackson's hurt.  He's fine. I've got a Fire Marshall shot, Detective Jackson is hurt but not seriously.",u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Detective Jackson', 'PERSON'), ('Fire Marshall', 'GPE'), ('Detective Jackson', 'PERSON')]",-0.6071
L3033,L3031,"Okay.  But I do understand that your partner, Leon Jackson's been injured. Is that correct?",u41,NICOLETTE,f,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[(""Leon Jackson's"", 'PERSON')]",-0.4767
L3031,L3031,"I understand, but I noticed that the Fire Marshall is here with you.  Is this somehow related to the fire department?",u41,NICOLETTE,f,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('the Fire Marshall', 'FAC')]",-0.7351
L2656,L2653,"Yeah, yeah.  Jesus.",u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Jesus', 'PERSON')]",0.5267
L2646,L2646,He's from Antigua.  His girlfriend was taking too long to put her make-up on. they were late for a party.  Stabbed her with a beer bottle.,u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Antigua', 'GPE'), ('Stabbed', 'PERSON')]",-0.0516
L2612,L2611,"My kids?  Let's see...Susan's 15. Aundrea's 9.  Don't tell me you're thinking about having a kid!  How old are you?  Never mind. Let me just tell you this: Every stupid cliche you hear about kids - they change your life, they make you a better person, they make you whole...  It's all true!  Before I had kids when friends talked about their kids, I wanted to vomit.  Now -- I get it.  Am I right, Leon?",u31,HAWKINS,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Susan', 'PERSON'), ('15', 'CARDINAL'), ('Aundrea', 'ORG'), ('9', 'CARDINAL'), ('Leon', 'PERSON')]",0.7596
L2606,L2604,"I think you're getting a little moody there, Eddie.",u31,HAWKINS,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Eddie', 'PERSON')]",-0.2975
L2605,L2604,"Not chopped up.  Not chopped up like that.  I mean, what do I got left? Coupla articles.  A medal or two. Plaque here and there and in a coupla years no one remembers me anymore.",u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('a coupla years', 'DATE')]",-0.0541
L2595,L2595,"So we're waitin' to hit this warrant - we got Emergency Service with the heavy weapons standin' by - ready to go.  I say, lemme get a cigar outta the car.  I go to get the cigar and BOOM!  All the sudden I turn around and a kid with a shotgun let one go.  Right where I was standin'.  That coulda been it.  I coulda had my head blown off and for what?  Some stupid kid got panicky, takes the safety off and it's over.  If I hadn't gone back for that cigar - for a bad habit - I would've had my head blown off.",u29,EDDIE,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Emergency Service', 'ORG'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.8718
L3278,L3278,Come to 45 Broadway.  Don't bring the Police.  Come alone or you'll be in my next film.,u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Broadway', 'FAC')]",-0.25
L3436,L3435,The Sheraton!  On Broadway!  Room 210. Go get Oleg.  He'll kill you.,u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Sheraton', 'ORG'), ('Broadway', 'FAC'), ('Oleg', 'PERSON')]",-0.7418
L2854,L2850,"Look.  Do we have a problem here? There's no reason to have a problem. I'm gonna make you feel real good.  You wanna Czech girl? After I'm done with you, you won't miss her.  Now why don't you pay me?",u32,HONEY,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Czech', 'NORP')]",-0.5423
L2847,L2845,"Baby, I'm anybody you want me to be. I'm a little schoolgirl, I'm mommy, I'm a Czech girl.",u32,HONEY,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Czech', 'NORP')]",0.0772
L2569,L2565,"Can you show me?  Sir, no cameras in the FIS area!",u33,IMMIGRATION OFFICER,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('FIS', 'ORG')]",-0.3595
L2566,L2565,Two weeks holiday.,u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Two weeks holiday', 'DATE')]",0.4019
L2565,L2565,What is your intended purpose of your visit to the United States?,u33,IMMIGRATION OFFICER,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('the United States', 'GPE')]",0.4215
L2914,L2910,"Hey, tabloids paid Ted Bundy - famous serial killer - half a million for his interview.  And how much you think Monica got for writing book about the President coming on to her?  It pays to be a killer or a whore in this country. Look, you want magazine or not?",u48,VENDOR,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Ted Bundy', 'PERSON'), ('Monica', 'PERSON')]",-0.932
L2913,L2910,Million?!  The killer gets one million dollars for a television interview?,u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('one million dollars', 'MONEY')]",-0.7142
L3378,L3376,"You think you are a director?  You are a fucking little, small Russian piece of shit.  And I hate you.  I fucking hate you.",u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Russian', 'NORP')]",-0.9001
L3375,L3372,Yes.  But there's only one problem - you want credit but the problem is - I don't share credit.,u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('one', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.0854
L3372,L3372,I'm serious...this - this is a great American film.  Full of violence and sex.  And I want my credit.,u42,OLEG,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('American', 'NORP')]",0.4404
L3357,L3356,"Oleg, don't be paranoid.  You got a hundred-fifty thousand dollars, didn't you?  I gave you half of what they gave me.  Look - here we are!",u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('a hundred-fifty thousand dollars', 'CARDINAL'), ('half', 'CARDINAL')]",0.2575
L3246,L3246,"No.  We are insane.  Who else but crazy men would film their murders?  So we kill someone famous and if we are caught, we are sent to mental hospital. But what good is money there?  Because once in hospital I say I not crazy. Just pretended to be acquitted.  We see psychiatrists.  They must certify we are sane and because of your - what is law called?  Oh - I got it.  Because of your Double Jeopardy law, we can't be tried for same crime twice.  We come out free, rich and famous!",u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Double Jeopardy', 'WORK_OF_ART')]",-0.9528
L3083,L3083,Gotta light the scene better.  Now it's more moody... like a scene from THE THIRD MAN.,u42,OLEG,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('THIRD', 'ORDINAL')]",0.6887
L2790,L2789,I'm homesick.  You have Eastern European girl?  A Czech girl?,u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Eastern European', 'NORP'), ('Czech', 'NORP')]",-0.264
L2779,L2778,I'm not filming.  I'm watching Milos die.  It's just like a move but realer.,u42,OLEG,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Milos', 'PERSON')]",-0.1779
L2668,L2666,"For five years I paid for your stupidness - you'll carry my bag for the rest of my life if I say so.  Unless you refuse, Oleg.",u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('five years', 'DATE'), ('Oleg', 'PERSON')]",-0.6326
L2639,L2639,Look.  New videocameras.  Color viewfinder.  Image stabilization. Solarization.  Night vision.,u42,OLEG,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Color', 'PERSON')]",0.25
L2638,L2635,Because I don't like your ugly language. I heard enough of it in school!  Now speak Czech or English.  And don't fool around anymore.  You almost got us thrown out!,u30,EMIL,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Czech', 'NORP'), ('English', 'LANGUAGE')]",0.5547
L2635,L2635,Look.  Times Square.  Just like in the movies!,u42,OLEG,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Times Square', 'FAC')]",0.4199
L2562,L2561,I want to document my trip to America.,u42,OLEG,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('America', 'GPE')]",0.0772
L2678,L2678,"Take your eyes off her, Oleg!  Look.  It wasn't my fault you two were caught.  It's his fault.  Trying to get the bank clerk's phone number?!  I wasn't going to wait!!!",u39,MILOS,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Oleg', 'PERSON'), ('two', 'CARDINAL')]",0.6892
L3410,L3409,"This footage will work in your favor. When the jury sees this - no matter what Cutler tries, they'll convict him.",u31,HAWKINS,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Cutler', 'PERSON')]",0.0772
L2590,L2582,"Yes.  No.  Both.  When I was a boy, I see movie at school called ""It's a Wonderful Life"" directed by Frank Capra. Ever since I want to come to America. Land of the free.  Home of the brave.  A land where anyone can be anything. As long as they are white.",u42,OLEG,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Frank Capra', 'PERSON'), ('America', 'GPE')]",0.9042
L2585,L2582,"Yes, we're in New York now.  But where are you planning to stay in New York?",u33,IMMIGRATION OFFICER,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('New York', 'GPE'), ('New York', 'GPE')]",0.2144
L2576,L2575,Okay.  You're a Czech national and you're a Russian national.  How do you know one another?,u33,IMMIGRATION OFFICER,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Czech', 'NORP'), ('Russian', 'NORP')]",0.2263
L2702,L2701,Fire Department?  Firemen don't carry guns.,u40,MUGGER,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Fire Department', 'ORG')]",-0.34
L2809,L2808,"Yeah, I'm religious.  I'm not an Atheist like you!  Now, are you guys gonna arrest me, or not?",u38,MAX,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Atheist', 'ORG')]",-0.3822
L2808,L2808,"What's that on your forehead, Max? That's a nice attention getter.",u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Max', 'PERSON')]",0.4215
L3025,L3024,"It hurts.  Aw, Jesus!",u35,KORFIN,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Jesus', 'PERSON')]",-0.5255
L2863,L2863,"-- From Czechoslovakia?  And how long have they been livin' in your building?  Alright, I'll be in touch when we know somethin'.  Milos and Tamina Karlova.  They were quiet and kept to themselves.  Landlord don't know who your girl is.",u35,KORFIN,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Czechoslovakia', 'GPE'), ('Milos', 'PERSON'), ('Tamina Karlova', 'PERSON'), ('Landlord', 'PERSON')]",0.3313
L2754,L2754,You see Eddie's face when I gave him the timer?  Wish I had a picture of it.,u35,KORFIN,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Eddie', 'PERSON')]",0.4019
L2735,L2735,"Mouth's clean, too.",u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Mouth', 'PERSON')]",0.4019
L2724,L2724,"Nah, not at all.  Detective Flemming - Bobby Korfin.  My Uncle Tony worked with you at 2-1 back when you were a rookie.",u35,KORFIN,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Nah', 'PERSON'), ('Bobby Korfin', 'PERSON'), ('Tony', 'PERSON'), ('2-1', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.1027
L3427,L3425,"GET OUTTA HERE NOW!!  GET IN THAT CAR AND DRIVE AWAY!!!  DO WHAT I SAY OR I'LL KILL YOU, TOO!!!",u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('KILL YOU', 'PERSON'), ('TOO', 'ORG')]",-0.7825
L3423,L3422,Don't you get it?  He knew he was gonna get caught!  That's why he videotaped Eddie's murder - he thinks he's gonna get off.,u34,JORDY,m,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Eddie', 'ORG')]",-0.7177
L2839,L2828,But doesn't the Son of Sam Law prevent criminals from profiting from their crimes?,u43,ROBERT HAWKINS,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Sam Law', 'PERSON')]",-0.3612
L2834,L2828,"Look, I'm a victim here, too.  I was a year away from getting my masters in Art, now I'll never graduate.  My life has been permanently disrupted.",u46,STEPHEN GELLER,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('a year', 'DATE'), ('Art', 'GPE')]",-0.2732
L2828,L2828,"This had nothing to do with shoes that didn't fit or my relationship with my father who, as you know, made a fortune selling penny loafers in the fifties. These people died because of the criminal actions of my doctor.",u46,STEPHEN GELLER,?,m2,15 minutes,2001,6.1,25854,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('the fifties', 'DATE')]",-0.8446
L3771,L3770,"I'm sorry, Dr. Smyslov, but I'm really not at liberty to discuss this.",u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Smyslov', 'PERSON')]",-0.6381
L3721,L3720,"I'm afraid I've only got a few minutes, but I'd love to.",u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('a few minutes', 'TIME')]",0.7783
L3713,L3712,"Well, how nice to see you again, Elena. You're looking wonderful.",u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Elena', 'ORG')]",0.8225
L4296,L4296,I didn't do that Frank. I took particular care not to freeze them.,u50,BOWMAN,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Frank', 'PERSON')]",0.4682
L4191,L4188,Well... Hal's reported the AO-unit about to fail again.,u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON'), ('AO', 'ORG')]",-0.5423
L4188,L4188,Good morning. How's it going?,u50,BOWMAN,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('morning', 'TIME')]",0.4404
L3979,L3979,"Not really. They just said it might be because we trained at Houston and they trained in Marshall, and that we're being charged against differ- ent accounting offices.",u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Houston', 'GPE'), ('Marshall', 'PERSON')]",-0.2023
L3972,L3972,"That's right. Well, naturally, I didn't say anything to Payroll. I assumed they'd start paying me at the higher grade on the next pay cheque. But it's been almost three weeks now and I'm still being paid as an AGS-18.",u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Payroll', 'ORG'), ('almost three weeks', 'DATE')]",0.09
L3969,L3963,Well I got the papers on my official up-grading to AGS-19 two weeks before we left.,u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('two weeks', 'DATE')]",0.2732
L3963,L3963,"Dave, if you've a minute, I'd like your advice on something.",u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON'), ('a minute', 'TIME')]",0.3612
L3942,L3942,"Hi. Frank... coming in, please.",u50,BOWMAN,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Frank', 'PERSON')]",0.3182
L4368,L4366,"Listen to me very carefully, Hal. Unless you immediately release the hibernation control and follow every order I give from this point on, I will immediately got to control central and carry out a complete disconnection.",u50,BOWMAN,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON')]",0.2006
L4367,L4366,"I know that you've had that on your mind for some time now, Dave, but it would be a crying shame, since I am so much more capable of carrying out this mission than you are, and I have such enthusiasm and confi- dence in the mission.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON')]",-0.0554
L4362,L4360,"I'm sorry, Dave, but in accordance with sub-routine C1532/4, quote, When the crew are dead or incapacitated, the computer must assume control, unquote. I must, therefore, override your authority now since you are not in any condition to intel- ligently exercise it.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON')]",-0.8885
L4360,L4360,"I can tell from the tone of your voice, Dave, that you're upset. Why don't you take a stress pill and get some rest.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON')]",-0.069
L4357,L4353,"I don't like to assert myself, Dave, but it would be much better now for you to rest. You've been involved in a very stressful situation.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON')]",-0.3807
L4355,L4353,"Look, Dave your've probably got a lot to do. I suggest you leave it to me.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON')]",-0.0516
L4354,L4353,"I'm goin to do this myself, Hal. Let me have the control, please.",u50,BOWMAN,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON')]",0.3182
L4350,L4346,"I don't really agree with you, Dave. My on-board memory store is more than capable of handling all the mission requirements.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON')]",0.141
L4349,L4346,"It doesn't have to be, Hal. It's more dangerous to be out of touch with Earth. Let me have manual control, please.",u50,BOWMAN,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON'), ('Earth', 'LOC')]",-0.2716
L4346,L4346,"I suppose it's because you've been under a lot of stress, but have you forgotten that they're not supposed to be revived for another three months.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('another three months', 'DATE')]",-0.5023
L4333,L4333,"Too bad about Frank, isn't it?",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Frank', 'PERSON')]",-0.5423
L4270,L4265,"Yes, it is, Hal.",u50,BOWMAN,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON')]",0.4019
L4266,L4265,"I'm sorry about the misunderstanding, Hal.",u50,BOWMAN,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON')]",-0.4767
L4265,L4265,"Naturally, Dave, I'm not pleased that the AO-unit has failed, but I hope at least this has restored your confidence in my integrity and reliability. I certainly wouldn't want to be disconnected, even temporarily, as I have never been disconnected in my entire service history.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON'), ('AO', 'ORG')]",0.9404
L4229,L4227,"Look, Dave, I know that you're sincere and that you're trying to do a competent job, and that you're trying to be helpful, but I can assure the problem is with the AO-units, and with your test gear.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON'), ('AO', 'ORG')]",0.4497
L4227,L4227,"I'm not questioning your word, Dave, but it's just not possible. I'm not capable of being wrong.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON')]",-0.7768
L4221,L4219,You know that we checked the two AO-units that you reported in imminent failure condition?,u50,BOWMAN,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('two', 'CARDINAL'), ('AO', 'ORG')]",-0.5106
L4220,L4219,"Sure, Dave, what's up?",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON')]",0.3182
L4219,L4219,"Not now, Hal, I'd like to talk to you about something.",u50,BOWMAN,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON')]",0.3612
L4080,L4079,"I understand Hal. We'll take care of it. Please, let me have the hard copy.",u50,BOWMAN,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON')]",0.6249
L4079,L4079,"The unit is still operational, Dave. but it will fail within seventy-two hours.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON'), ('seventy-two hours', 'TIME')]",-0.6956
L4068,L4068,"Sorry to interrupt the festivities, Dave, but I think we've got a problem.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Dave', 'PERSON')]",-0.5187
L4006,L4006,"I'm sorry, Frank, but I don't think I can answer that question without knowing everything that all of you know.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Frank', 'PERSON')]",-0.0387
L3688,L3688,"Okay, sweetheart. Have a lovely Birthday Party tomorrow.",u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('tomorrow', 'DATE')]",0.9136
L3685,L3679,"Three, darling. One... two ... three. Be sure to tell Mommy I called.",u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Three', 'CARDINAL'), ('One', 'CARDINAL'), ('Mommy', 'PERSON')]",0.7269
L3683,L3679,"Okay, sweetheart. Well, I have to go now. Tell Mommy that I called.",u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Tell Mommy', 'PERSON')]",0.8074
L3677,L3672,"In three days, darling, I hope.",u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('three days', 'DATE')]",0.7717
L3675,L3672,"No, I'm sorry, darling, I told you I won't be home for a few days.",u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('a few days', 'DATE')]",0.3182
L3672,L3672,I'm having a party tomorrow.,u52,CHILD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('tomorrow', 'DATE')]",0.4019
L3808,L3805,"Yes, well, whatever it is, they're certainly not fooling around. This is the first flight they allowed in for more than a week.",u59,PILOT,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('more than a week', 'DATE')]",0.8155
L3780,L3779,Thank you. It's been a great pleasure to meet all of you... Dr. Smyslov.,u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Smyslov', 'PERSON')]",0.8834
L3779,L3779,"Well, Gregor and I will look forward to seeing you.",u54,ELENA,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Gregor', 'PERSON')]",0.2732
L3776,L3774,"Well, I hope that you and your wife can come to the I.A.C. conference in June.",u54,ELENA,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('I.A.C.', 'ORG'), ('June', 'DATE')]",0.6124
L3734,L3730,He's fine. But I'm afraid we don't get a chance to see each other very much these days.,u54,ELENA,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('these days', 'DATE')]",-0.1803
L3731,L3730,"Oh, she's growing up very fast. As a matter of fact, she's six tomorrow.",u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('six', 'CARDINAL'), ('tomorrow', 'DATE')]",0.2648
L3630,L3626,"Well, shall we go through Documentation?",u58,MILLER,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Documentation', 'ORG')]",0.2732
L3772,L3772,"This epidemic could easily spread to our base, Dr. Floyd. We should be given all the facts.",u61,SMYSLOV,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Floyd', 'PERSON')]",0.34
L3768,L3766,"Quite frankly, we have had some very reliable intelligence reports that a quite serious epidemic has broken out at Clavius. Something, apperently, of an unknown origin. Is this, in fact, what has happened?",u61,SMYSLOV,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Clavius', 'GPE')]",-0.081
L3766,L3766,"Dr. Floyd, at the risk of pressing you on a point you seem reticent to discuss, may I ask you a straightforward question?",u61,SMYSLOV,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Floyd', 'PERSON')]",-0.2732
L3760,L3760,"Yes, and I'm afaid there's going to be a bit of a row about it. Denying the men permission to land was a direct violation of the I.A.S. convention.",u61,SMYSLOV,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('I.A.S.', 'GPE')]",-0.4404
L3751,L3751,"Yes, well at first we thought that was the explanation, but it's been going on for the past ten days.",u61,SMYSLOV,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('first', 'ORDINAL'), ('the past ten days', 'DATE')]",0.34
L3748,L3745,"Yes. Well, for one thing, whenever you phone the base, all you can get is a recording which repeats that the phone lines are temporarily out of order.",u61,SMYSLOV,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('one', 'CARDINAL')]",0.5859
L3746,L3745,"Well, it's just for the past two weeks there have been some extremely odd things happening at Clavius.",u61,SMYSLOV,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('the past two weeks', 'DATE'), ('Clavius', 'ORG')]",-0.1263
L3739,L3738,"Are you, by any chance, going up to your base at Clavius?",u61,SMYSLOV,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Clavius', 'ORG')]",0.25
L3907,L3904,"I don't think it has, but I'd like to check that. Simpson, what's the log on that?",u57,MICHAELS,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Simpson', 'PERSON')]",0.5023
L3905,L3904,"Well, not really. At first glance, black would suggest something sun-powered, but then why would anyone deliberately bury a sun- powered device?",u57,MICHAELS,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('first', 'ORDINAL')]",0.1406
L3889,L3889,"Yes, it does. The sub-surface structure shows that it was deliberately buried about four million years ago.",u57,MICHAELS,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('about four million years ago', 'DATE')]",0.4019
L3869,L3868,I'm afraid it can and it will be kept under wraps as long as it is deemed to be necessary by the Council. And of course you know that the Council has requested that formal security oaths are to be obtained in writing from every- one who had any knowledge of this event. There must be adequate time for a full study to be made of the situation before any con- sideration can be given to making a public announcement.,u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Council', 'ORG'), ('Council', 'ORG')]",0.5106
L3838,L3837,"No, of course, Captain, I can understand your concern.",u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Captain', 'PERSON')]",-0.296
L3834,L3832,"Yes, well, I wouldn't have been too concerned about it, except I've heard these stories about the epidemic and, as a matter of fact, I've heard that ten people have died already.",u59,PILOT,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('ten', 'CARDINAL')]",0.0772
L3832,L3832,"Well, I'll tell you why I ask. You see, I've got a girl who works in the Auditing Department of the Territorial Administrator and I haven't been able to get her on the phone for the past week or so, and with all these stories one hears, I'm a little concerned about her.",u59,PILOT,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('the Auditing Department of the Territorial Administrator', 'ORG'), ('the past week', 'DATE'), ('one', 'CARDINAL')]",0.2732
L3829,L3824,I take it this is something to do with the trouble they're having up at Clavius?,u59,PILOT,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Clavius', 'ORG')]",-0.4019
L3827,L3824,Well... the crew is confined to the ship when we land at Clavius. We have to stay inside for the time it take to refit - about twenty-four hours. And then we're going to back empty.,u59,PILOT,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Clavius', 'ORG')]",-0.2023
L3825,L3824,"Incidentally, Dr. Floyd, I wonder if I can have a word with you about the security arrangements?",u59,PILOT,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Floyd', 'PERSON')]",0.34
L3821,L3817,"Oh, no, thank you. The two girls have taken wonderful care of me. I'm just fine.",u55,FLOYD,?,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('two', 'CARDINAL')]",0.8402
L4183,L4181,"All right, Hal. We'll take care of it. Let me have the hard copy, please.",u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON')]",0.6249
L4174,L4174,"I know you did, Frank, but I assure you there was an impending failure.",u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Frank', 'PERSON')]",-0.3291
L4170,L4169,It looks like we have another bad A.O. unit. My FPC shows another impending failure.,u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('A.O.', 'NORP'), ('FPC', 'ORG')]",-0.6486
L4169,L4169,"Yes, Hal, what's up?",u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON')]",0.4019
L4118,L4118,Pod Bay is decompressed. All doors are secure. You are free to open pod bay doors.,u56,HAL,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Pod Bay', 'LOC')]",0.6908
L4096,L4096,"Hal, have pod arms secure the component.",u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON')]",0.34
L4033,L4028,"Thank you very much, Hal.",u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON')]",0.3612
L4029,L4028,"Approximately five years after we go into hibernation, the recovery vehicle will make rendezous with us and bring us back. Is this true?",u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Approximately five years', 'DATE')]",0.5023
L4024,L4020,Our transit time is 257 days. Is that true?,u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('257 days', 'DATE')]",0.4215
L4022,L4020,Our Mission Profile calls for Discovery going to Saturn. True or false?,u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Discovery', 'PRODUCT'), ('Saturn', 'PRODUCT')]",0.4215
L4020,L4020,"Right. Hal, tell me whether the following statements are true or false.",u60,POOLE,m,m3,2001: a space odyssey,1968,7.3,163227,"[, ', a, d, v, e, n, t, u, r, e, ', ,,  , ', m, y, s, t, e, r, y, ', ,,  , ', s, c, i, -, f, i, ', ]","[('Hal', 'PERSON')]",0.4215
L4899,L4897,Maybe you better have a Black Russian.,u63,BARTENDER,?,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('a Black Russian', 'NORP')]",0.4404
L4563,L4562,"He's just kiddin', you just keep doin' what I tell ya, you'll be okay.",u64,BILLY,?,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('kiddin', 'PERSON')]",0.2263
L4453,L4453,"Maybe you shoulda stole a better truck, Tonto.",u69,GANZ,?,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Tonto', 'GPE')]",0.4404
L5370,L5370,"I'll buy ya the best dinner in San Francisco...how'd that be? Then we'll go dancin', okay?",u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('San Francisco', 'GPE')]",0.755
L5184,L5183,"Yeah, i been waiting three years.",u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('three years', 'DATE')]",0.296
L5176,L5175,"Excuse me, baby, but if i don't get some action tonight, I'm gonna bust.  You interested?",u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('tonight', 'TIME')]",0.5719
L4960,L4959,I used to go with him...I don't know where the hell he is.  I haven't seen him for two weeks. And I don't think I will.  He owes me money...,u66,CASEY,?,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('two weeks', 'DATE')]",-0.6808
L5384,L5383,"No trouble, Jack. But, listen, suppose I stay a crook?  Where'd you get the idea that you could catch me?",u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Jack', 'PERSON')]",-0.4234
L5375,L5375,"Wait a minute, Cates.  I've been waitin' three years for that.  I don't think it's fair, man. What about the merit system.? You were gonnna give me a few thousand.",u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('a minute', 'TIME'), ('Cates', 'GPE'), (""' three years"", 'DATE'), ('a few thousand', 'CARDINAL')]",0.2115
L5373,L5372,"Hey, Jack, real men don't have to go in for that macho bullshit ... but I was fantastic.",u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Jack', 'PERSON')]",0.5423
L5352,L5351,Yeah.  But I wasn't there for a second.,u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('second', 'ORDINAL')]",0.1531
L5312,L5308,"Yeah, and I know Ganz sure ain't no sweetheart... I wouldn't like it if this partnership ended before it gets started.",u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Ganz', 'PERSON')]",0.507
L5311,L5308,"Sure, I'll give you a shot at it, but Ganz is mine.  You know, that big Indian plays it for keeps...",u67,CATES,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Ganz', 'PERSON'), ('Indian', 'NORP')]",0.4854
L5306,L5306,"What if your girl's theory turns out to be bullshit?  I mean, they could be in Rio de Janeiro.",u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Rio de Janeiro', 'GPE')]",-0.5859
L5291,L5290,"Yeah, too bad.  They were real nice lookin' too...In bed together, hardly any clothes one watching TV...",u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('one', 'CARDINAL')]",0.128
L5290,L5290,"Yeah, well the only woman of the Indian's we ran into was shacked up with her dyke girlfriend.  I guess she went with him before she came outta the Closet ... They both looked mad enough to kill him...",u67,CATES,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Indian', 'NORP')]",-0.6808
L5253,L5253,"Sorry we didn't do better, Jack. I feel like I let you down.",u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Jack', 'PERSON')]",-0.0531
L5237,L5236,Yeah. It missed the last four stops.,u67,CATES,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('four', 'CARDINAL')]",-0.1531
L5236,L5236,Notice something funny about that bus?,u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Notice', 'ORG')]",0.4404
L5225,L5224,"When you been in prison three years, it don't take long. Let's go.",u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('three years', 'DATE')]",-0.5106
L5209,L5208,"Bein' good at your job don't explain everything, Jack ...",u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Jack', 'PERSON')]",0.4404
L5208,L5208,"Thanks for callin' in... and I guess Maybe... Look, I'm sorry I called you Watermellon nigger... those kinds of things. I was just leanin' on ya, doin' my job.",u67,CATES,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Watermellon', 'PRODUCT')]",0.3818
L5205,L5204,Forget it. I want Ganz as bad as you do and I got some other news for you...,u71,HAMMOND,m,m4,48 hrs.,1982,6.9,22289,"[, ', a, c, t, i, o, n, ', ,,  , ', c, o, m, e, d, y, ', ,,  , ', c, r, i, m, e, ', ,,  , ', d, r, a, m, a, ', ,,  , ', t, h, r, i, l, l, e, r, ', ]","[('Ganz', 'PERSON')]",-0.6249
